[
    {
        "question": "अनिवार्य",
        "options": [
            "ऐच्छिक",
            "पृष्ठांकित",
            "आवश्यक",
            "वैकल्पिक"
        ],
        "answer": "ऐच्छिक"
    },
    {
        "question": "कृपा",
        "options": [
            "आवेश",
            "उदेग",
            "आवेग",
            "कोप"
        ],
        "answer": "कोप"
    },
    {
        "question": "ज्येष्ठ",
        "options": [
            "कनिष्ठ",
            "लघु",
            "अनुज",
            "छोटा"
        ],
        "answer": "कनिष्ठ"
    },
    {
        "question": "संयोग",
        "options": [
            "वियोग",
            "विघटन",
            "दैवयोग",
            "विप्रयोग"
        ],
        "answer": "वियोग"
    },
    {
        "question": "स्थूल",
        "options": [
            "स्वल्प",
            "अभौतिक",
            "पारलौकिक",
            "सूक्ष्म"
        ],
        "answer": "सूक्ष्म"
    },
    {
        "question": "अच्छा",
        "options": [
            "खराब",
            "भ्रष्ट",
            "बुरा",
            "गंदा"
        ],
        "answer": "बुरा"
    },
    {
        "question": "अगला",
        "options": [
            "पिछला",
            "पश्च",
            "आगामी",
            "विगत"
        ],
        "answer": "पिछला"
    },
    {
        "question": "अचल",
        "options": [
            "स्थिर",
            "चेतन",
            "चल",
            "गतिशील"
        ],
        "answer": "चल"
    },
    {
        "question": "अनागत",
        "options": [
            "आगत",
            "वर्तमान",
            "भूतकालिक",
            "विगत"
        ],
        "answer": "आगत"
    },
    {
        "question": "अथ",
        "options": [
            "इति",
            "समाप्त",
            "पूर्व",
            "खत्म"
        ],
        "answer": "इति"
    },
    {
        "question": "अभिज्ञ",
        "options": [
            "अनभिज्ञ",
            "मूर्ख",
            "निपुणताहीन",
            "अज्ञानी"
        ],
        "answer": "अनभिज्ञ"
    },
    {
        "question": "अनुग्रह",
        "options": [
            "पाना",
            "लेना",
            "विग्रह",
            "स्वीकारना"
        ],
        "answer": "विग्रह"
    },
    {
        "question": "अर्पण",
        "options": [
            "ग्रहण",
            "स्वीकृति",
            "याचना",
            "प्राप्ति"
        ],
        "answer": "ग्रहण"
    },
    {
        "question": "अपमान",
        "options": [
            "आदर",
            "सम्मान",
            "मान",
            "अभिनन्दन"
        ],
        "answer": "सम्मान"
    },
    {
        "question": "अंतरंग",
        "options": [
            "बाहरी",
            "अप्राप्य",
            "बहिरंग",
            "शत्रु"
        ],
        "answer": "बहिरंग"
    },
    {
        "question": "अधुनातन",
        "options": [
            "प्राचीन",
            "विगतकालीन",
            "पुरातन",
            "मूर्तकालिक"
        ],
        "answer": "पुरातन"
    },
    {
        "question": "अंत",
        "options": [
            "शुरू",
            "श्रीगणेश",
            "अथ",
            "प्रारम्भ"
        ],
        "answer": "प्रारम्भ"
    },
    {
        "question": "अल्पज्ञ",
        "options": [
            "बहुज्ञ",
            "बहुश्रुत",
            "सर्वज्ञ",
            "विदान्"
        ],
        "answer": "बहुज्ञ"
    },
    {
        "question": "अज्ञ",
        "options": [
            "विज्ञ",
            "पारंगत",
            "सर्वज्ञ",
            "अनभिज्ञ"
        ],
        "answer": "विज्ञ"
    },
    {
        "question": "अवनि",
        "options": [
            "आसमान",
            "अम्बर",
            "आकाश",
            "नभ"
        ],
        "answer": "अम्बर"
    },
    {
        "question": "अगम",
        "options": [
            "सरल",
            "सहल",
            "सुगम",
            "साधारण"
        ],
        "answer": "सुगम"
    },
    {
        "question": "अत्यधिक",
        "options": [
            "तनिक",
            "न्यून",
            "जरासा",
            "स्वल्प"
        ],
        "answer": "स्वल्प"
    },
    {
        "question": "आशा",
        "options": [
            "हताशा",
            "निराशा",
            "दुराशा",
            "ना उम्मीदी"
        ],
        "answer": "निराशा"
    },
    {
        "question": "अवनत",
        "options": [
            "उच्च",
            "उन्नत",
            "उत्कर्ष",
            "नत"
        ],
        "answer": "उन्नत"
    },
    {
        "question": "अपेक्षा",
        "options": [
            "निन्दा",
            "अस्वीकार",
            "उपेक्षा",
            "तिरस्कार"
        ],
        "answer": "उपेक्षा"
    }
]